'위기의 주부들'
지난 이야기
Previously on Desperate Housewives...
모든 미스터리에는
동기가 있다
There is a motive to every mystery...
내가 처방한 약에
전혀 반응을 안 하고 있어
Your body isn't responding
to the medication the way it should.
- 심장마비가 온 것 같아
- 모든 범죄에는 증거가 있다
- I think I'm having a heart attack.
-..evidence of every crime...
증오범죄로
기소했다는 말이에요?
They're charging you with a hate crime?
- 당신하고 바람피운 줄 알았어
- 게이 케이블 기사하고요?
- I thought you were cheating with him.
- With our gay cable guy?
게이인 줄 알 턱이 있어?
저스틴이 게이인 것도 전혀 몰랐어
I didn't know he was gay.
I didn't know Justin was either.
그리고 모든 의문엔
해답이 있다
..and an answer to every question.
한 여자가 자살을 했어
분명 무슨 일이 있었던 거야
Gabby, the woman killed herself.
Something must have been going on.
아주 가까이에서
바라보기만 하면...
All you have to do
is take a closer look.
여자 유골이 있었어
토막 살해된 여자
It had a woman in it.
She was all chopped up.
- 결국 모든 비밀은...
- 어디 있는지 알아요?
- And eventually, every secret...
- Do you know where Paul Young is?
목요일 밤에
어디 있을진 알아요
I know where he'll be on Thursday night.
드러나게 되어있다
..will be revealed.
- 협박을 받았단 말이야?
- 대체 무슨 일이야?
- Mary Alice was being blackmailed?
- Mary Alice, what did you do?
내 이름은 메리 앨리스 영
My name is Mary Alice Young.
죽기 전 내 인생은
사랑, 웃음, 우정
Before I died, my life was filled
with love, laughter, friendship,
그리고 비밀로 채워졌었다
and sadly, secrets.
비밀은 내가 죽기 15년 전
내가 앤젤라였을 때 시작되었다
The secrets had begun 15 years earlier
when my name was Angela Forrest,
그때 난 아주 절망적인 삶을
살고 있었다
and I was living a life
of quiet desperation.
매일 아침
남편 아침을 차려주면서도...
I'd feel it every morning
as I made breakfast for my husband.
장보러 가면 면도크림 좀 사
다 떨어졌어
Could you could stop by the market?
I'm out of shaving cream.
오후 내내
집안 일을 보면서도...
And during the errands
I ran in the afternoons...
금요일엔 더
싸게 사실 수 있어요
You'll save a bunch
if you come on Fridays.
직장에서 야간근무를 할 때도
난 늘 불행했다
..even at my work every evening...
정말 멋있다
어디서 찍은 거지?
What a lovely calendar.
Was this taken around here?
페어뷰야
거기 가족이 살아서 알아
No, that's way out in Fairview.
I have family there.
정말 멋진 곳이지?
Isn't it idyllic?
이 기록 좀 정리해줄래?
Here, Angela. You can file this.
내게 하루하루는
의미없는 무채색이었다
..to me, each day
was gray and meaningless.
그러던 어느 날 밤
갑자기
And then one night, suddenly...
- 안녕, 앤젤라
- 내 삶에 색이 입혀졌다
- Hey, Angela.
-..there was color.
데어드레?
여긴 어쩐 일이야?
Deidre? What are you doing here?
돈이 필요해
I need some money.
데어드레? 마셔
Deidre. Here.
- 아직 못 끊은거지?
- 아니
- You're using again, aren't you?
- No.
아기 우유하고
몇 가지 살 게 있어서 그래
I've just got to get some food
for my baby. Some other stuff.
아기 우유가 필요하면
같이 가서 사줄게
If the baby's hungry, come to the market
and I'll buy food.
그 정도는 나 혼자서도 할 수 있어
I can shop for my own baby, OK?
조용해!
정신이 하나도 없잖아
Quiet. I can't think.
이거 아주 비싼 시계야
이거 갖고 50달러만 줘
See this watch? It's worth a lot.
I'll give it to you for 50 bucks.
- 돈은 줄 수 없어요
- 좀 빠져줄래요?
- She's not giving you money.
- Do you mind?
재활원에서 날 사람처럼 대해준 건
앤젤라 밖에 없었어
Angela, you're the only one at rehab
who treated me like a person.
제발 사정 좀 봐줘
Please don't stop now.
미안해
I'm sorry.
그럼 내 아기를 팔게
I'll sell you my baby.
- 뭐?
- 아기 못 낳는 거 알아
- What?
- I know you can't have your own.
- 그래서 괴로워하고 있잖아
- 그만 가줘요
- It's been killing you.
- It's time that you left.
앤젤라라면 우리 데이나를
잘 키울 수 있을 거고
I'm thinking about Dana.
You'll give him a good home.
데이나를 위해서도
그게 좋을거야
OK? He'll be better off.
조용히 해
Quiet.
여보
Honey.
지금 가진 돈이
다 얼마야?
How much money
do you keep in the house?
10개월 된 아들이 있었는데
애는 못 봤어요?
She has a ten-month-old baby.
Where is it?
모르겠어요
있었으면 데리고 나왔겠죠
I don't know. If we'd seen a kid we
wouldn't have left it in a crack house.
- 애가 잘못되면 가만 안 있겠어요
- 그럼 이렇게 하죠
- I will have your badge.
- Just let me do my job.
경찰관 한 명이
여기서 지키고 있다가
We'll post an officer
at the junkie's bedside,
정신이 드는대로
애가 있는곳을 확인하겠어요
we'll let her tell us
where she left her kid.
"페어뷰 시
1990년 3월"
페어뷰에서 행복하시길 바랍니다
I really do hope you folks
will be happy here in Fairview.
고마워요
Thank you.
- 그리고 우린 행복했다
- 인사해야지, 재크
- And we were.
- Wave bye, Zach.
안녕히 가세요
Wave bye-bye.
다른 가족들과 다름없이
행복한 나날을 보냈다
We were as happy as any family could be.
하지만 3년 후
어느 날 밤
Until one night three years later...
문 두드리는 소리가
들린 이후...
when there was a knock at our door.
다시 내 불행은 시작됐다
And I was desperate once again.
"위기의 주부들"
새벽 5시, 위스테리아 레인에
전화벨이 울릴 때는
It was 5:00 in the morning on Wisteria
Lane when the phone calls started.
무엇인가
잘못된 신호라는 것을
Each of them knew something was wrong
누구나 알아차렸다
from that first ring.
여보세요?
Hello?
그건 이미 공공연한
규칙 같은 것이었다
It's an unwritten rule of suburbia...
여보세요?
Hello?
나쁜 일이 아니라면
Don't call the neighbors
한밤중에
in the middle of the night
절대 전화를 걸지 마라
unless the news is bad.
여보세요?
Hello?
그렇게 그들은 모였다
And so they came,
헝클어진 머리와
with their uncombed hair
잠에서 깬
부스스한 얼굴로
and their unmade faces.
그들이 모인 이유는
They came because
몇 년을 함께 보낸 후
after all these years...
브리
Bree.
그들은 더 이상 단순한 이웃이
아니었기 때문이다
.. they were no longer just neighbors.
여기까지 어쩐 일이야?
What are you doing here?
렉스가 심장마비로
응급실에 왔다며?
We heard Rex had a heart attack.
어때?
How is he?
한 고비는 넘겼어
He's stable.
계속 지켜보다가
But they have to put in a pacemaker,
수술을 해야하나봐
so they're gonna need to operate.
- 어떻게 알았어?
- 다니엘이 전화 했어
- How did you guys know?
- Danielle called.
자긴 어때?
So how are you doing?
부부싸움을 하다가
이렇게 됐어
We were having a fight when he
got the heart attack and...
더 일찍 데려왔어야 하는데
내 잘못이야
I'm feeling guilty'cause I should have
gotten him here sooner and...
모두 실력있는
의사들이잖아
Honey, the doctors here are great.
그래, 젊으니까
곧 일어날거야
He's gonna bounce right back.
걱정할거 하나도 없어
You have nothing to worry about.
모두 와줘서 정말기뻐
진심이야
You know what? I am so happy
that you guys came here. I really am.
하지만 약해지지 않으려고
마음을 다잡고 있는데
But I am trying hard to be strong,
자기들이 자꾸 위로를 하면...
so if you keep comforting me...
약해질 것 같아?
You're gonna lose it?
그럼 위로 안 할게
Then we won't comfort.
고마워
Thank you.
그럼 편안한 얘기나 하자
We'll just talk about non-crisis things.
나 하나 있어!
마이크 차에서
I know. I found Mrs. Huber's journal
후버부인 일기장을 찾았어
in some of Mike's stuff.
메리 앨리스 비밀을 가지고
협박한 사람이
She knew Mary Alice's secret
바로 후버 부인이었어
and was blackmailing her.
아주 편안한 얘기다
Yep, that'll do it.
재크, 이리 돌아와
Zachary, come back here, please.
아빠가 돌아오실 때까지
나하고 있으라고 했잖니
Your father said
you should let me look after you.
저 혼자서도 충분해요
전 어린애가 아니에요
I will be fine by myself.
I am not a child.
너 어린애 아닌 거 알아
I know you're not a child,
하지만 혼자서 지내게
둘 수는 없어
but I think we should discuss this.
전 괜찮아요
정말이에요
I'm fine. Really.
우리 집에 와 있어도 된다니까
Why should you fend for yourself
왜 혼자 있겠다고
고집을 부리니?
when you can just come home with me?
나한테 얼마든지 의지해
기꺼이 힘이 돼줄게
Let me shoulder the burden.
It would be my pleasure.
도대체 왜 이래요?
날 좀 가만둬요!
What kind of freak are you?
Just leave me alone.
우리 엄마도 아니잖아요!
You are not my mother.
괜찮다고 몇 번을 말해요?
엄마흉내 그만내고 가요!
I told you that I am fine.
Stop acting like my mother and go home.
나도 그렇게
할 수 있으면 좋겠구나
I wish it were that easy, Zachary,
널 위해서라도 말이야
for your sake.
하지만 그럴 수가 없어
But it's not.
아빠는 돌아오시지 않아
Your father's not coming back.
- 돌아오신다고 했어요
- 거짓말이야
- He said that he was.
- He lied.
나도 그렇게
말해주고 싶지만
I wanted to spare you this,
아빠하고 얘기했었단다
but your father and I discussed it
영원히 돌아오지 않기로
and he decided
결심하고 떠나셨어
that he shouldn't come back.
그러니까 짐 챙겨서
집으로 가자
Get your bag and let's go home.
푸딩 만들어줄게
I'm gonna make you some pudding.
우리 아빠한테
무슨 짓을 한 거야!
What did you do to my dad?
말해!
Tell me.
애플화이트 부인?
Mrs. Applewhite?
네?
Yes?
안녕하세요
이디 브릿이에요
Hi. I'm Edie Britt.
이 집 소개한 중개인이요
The realtor who helped you
buy this house.
네, 안녕하세요
Of course. Hi.
한 번 꼭 뵙고 싶었어요
Hi. I've been so curious to meet you.
그래요? 왜요?
Really? Why?
전화로만 집을 팔아보긴
처음이라서요
It's just that I've never sold a house
over the phone before.
보지도않고 결정하시다니
용기가 대단하세요
You were brave
buying a place site unseen.
뭘요
Not really.
딱 우리가 찾던 집이에요
It was just what we were looking for.
제 아들 매튜예요
This is my son, Matthew.
반갑습니다, 부인
It's nice to meet you, ma'am.
그냥 이디라고 불러줘
Please, call me Edie.
부인이란 말은
나이든 여자한테나 쓰는 말이지
Ma'am is for middle-aged women.
저 아줌마처럼!
Like her.
저 아줌마는 언제든지
그렇게 부르렴
You can call her ma'am
any time you want.
별 문제는 없나요?
So are you two finding everything OK?
집을 보여드리지 못해서
좀 걱정이 됐거든요
We didn't do
our realtor's walkthrough.
아무 문제없어요
Everything is fine.
계약은 다 끝났으니까
Honey. Escrow's closed.
비가오면 어디가 새는지
솔직하게 알려 드릴게요
Now I can show you where
to put the buckets when it rains.
이디, 아무 이상없어요
Edie, the house is fine.
이렇게 와준 건
정말 고맙게 생각해요
But how lovely of you to stop by.
명함이에요
OK. Here is my card.
언제든 도움이 필요하면
전화하세요
Call any time you want.
안녕
Bye.
이 동네 사람들은
아주 친절하네요
People are very friendly
in this neighborhood.
그래, 그렇구나
Yes. Yes, they are.
마이크, 나예요
일은 잘 돼 가요?
Mike, hi, sweetie.
I hope the job's going well.
화내지 말아요
So I hope you're not mad
당신 트럭에서
후버 부인 일기장을 주웠어요
but I found Mrs. Huber's journal
in your truck
도저히 참을 수가 없어서
다 읽었고
and I couldn't exactly not read it,
so I did,
협박에 대해서 알게 됐어요
전화해줘요, 얘기 좀 해요
and I know all about the blackmail,
so call me, we'll talk.
사랑해요, 안녕
Love you. Bye.
계속 연락이 안 오니까
걱정이 돼 미치겠어요
I haven't heard back
and I was getting a little concerned.
아무래도 폴이
후버 부인을 죽인 것 같아요
The girls and I were talking and we
think maybe Paul Young killed Mrs. Huber
그리고 당신 옛 친구도
폴이 죽였을 가능성이 커요
and if he did
maybe he killed your old girlfriend too
제발 전화 좀 해요
사랑해요
so we should really talk about this,
so call me. I love you. Bye.
휴대폰은 도대체
왜 가지고 다녀요?
I thought the whole point
of having a cell phone
급할 때 연락하라고
있는 거 아니에요?
was so someone could reach you.
이렇게 연락도 안 하면서
같이 산다고 할 수 있어요?
How can we move forward
if you won't communicate with me?
마이크, 당장 전화해요
나 진짜 화났어요
Mike, I need you to call me back.
I mean it.
사랑해요, 안녕
Love you. Bye.
지난 번 메시지는 미안해요
I'm so sorry for that last phone call.
너무 걱정이 돼서 그랬어요
Let's just say it was the worry talking.
얘기할 게 많아요
I just really need to talk to you.
잠깐만요
전화왔어요
Can you hang on? I got another call.
- 여보세요
- 나예요
- Hello.
- Hey, it's me.
세상에!
도대체 어디 있어요?
My God. Where have you been?
여기 휴대폰이 잘 안터져요
메시지는 들었어요
The reception's lousy up here
but I got your messages.
지난 번 메시지는 미안해요
I'm really sorry for that last message.
- 내가 너무...
- 날카로워져서?
- I was just...
- Stressed out?
그래요, 날카로워졌었어요
Yes, let's call it stressed out.
후버 부인 일기는
어디서 난 거예요?
So how did you get
Martha Huber's journal?
동생이 줬어요
Her sister, Mrs. Tillman,
gave it to me.
찾는 걸 도와주고 싶다면서요
She was helping me with my search.
아무래도 경찰에
넘겨주는 게 좋겠어요
I really think we need
to give it to the police.
그래요
Yeah.
- 그래야죠
- 정말이요?
- Yeah, absolutely.
- Really?
이번 일이 끝나고 나면
When I get through with this job,
코프랜드 형사한테
연락을 하는 게 좋겠어요
we'll make an appointment
with that detective. Copeland.
정말 잘 생각했어요
Great. That's great.
몇 시간만 더 기다려요
All right.
So I'll see you in a few hours.
알았어요, 하지만 서둘러요
아무래도 폴이 범인인 것 같아요
OK. Hurry, though. I have a feeling Paul
Young is in the middle of all of this.
섣부르게 판단하진 말아요
Well, let's not rush to judgment.
- 당신이 어쩐 일이야?
- 증언하러 왔어요
- What are you doing here?
- I'm here to testify for you.
저것 좀 풀어주시겠어요?
옷을 입힐수가 없잖아요
Can you take those off?
There's no way I'm dressing him.
결심해줘서 정말 고마워
Gabby, thank God you're doing this.
두 번째 주먹질이
치명적이었어
Beating up a second gay guy looks bad.
맞아요, 누가 그러는데
Yes, well, Carlos, in some circles,
폭행은 아주 악질 범죄래요
beating people up at all
is frowned upon.
마음을 바꾼 이유가 뭐야?
So why did you change your mind?
난 조금 있으면
당신 아이의 엄마가 돼요
I'm about to be
the mother of your child,
그건 곧 많은 책임이 생기고
시간을 잃게 된다는 의미죠
which means a lot of responsibility
and little time for myself.
그러니까 당신을 구해주면
당신도 그만큼 보답을 해요
So if I'm gonna get you out of
this mess, you have to reciprocate.
좋아
OK.
아기가 밤에 울면
When the baby cries
during the night,
당신은 군소리없이
일어나야 돼요
you're going to get up,
without saying one word.
병원에 가는 것도 당신이 맡고
내 차는 절대로 안돼요
Doctor's appointments, you're driving.
I won't put a car seat in my Maserati.
그리고 우유도
당신이 책임져요
And you will also be on bottle duty.
우유병 닦고 소독하는 것도
물론 다 포함이에요
That means washing,
sterilizing and filling.
그럼 속 마음이야 어떻건
완벽한 부부로 살아줄게요
I'll have some semblance of a life
and maybe I won't hate you so much.
자, 다 됐어요
All right. There we go.
그럼 얘기 끝난 거죠?
So we're good?
- 법정에서 봐요
- 여보
- See you in court.
- Hey, Gabby.
모유는 안 먹여?
Aren't we breastfeeding?
일찌감치 포기하는 게
신상에 좋을 거예요
Honey, if you can swing that one,
more power to you.
내 피자는 내가살래요
Can I buy my own pizza?
나중에 돈 낼 수 있을 때
그렇게 해
You can, honey, if you can pay for it.
19점! 19점이야
더 열심히 해봐
That is 19, 19, 19-zip. Bring it.
잠깐 동생 좀 보고 있어
Just stay here with Penny
for a second, OK?
여보
Tom.
어때, 똑똑히 봤지?
20점! 게임 끝이야
Yes. In your face.
That is 20-zip. Game. Out.
여보, 여기서 뭐해?
Tom. What are you doin'?
하키 하는 거 안 보여?
케빈, 네 차례야
Playing air hockey, what does it
look like? Kevin, you're up.
회사에 있을 시간에
왜 여기 있느냐는 말이지
It's the middle of the day.
Shouldn't you be at work?
회사 그만뒀어
No. I quit.
- 말도 안돼!
- 사실이야
- You did not.
- Yes.
어제 사장한테 얘기했어
Yesterday.
Told Peterson he could stick it.
더 힘을 내보라니까!
그래선 어림없어
Boom. You're not bringing it, Kevin.
Bring it.
나한테 한 마디 상의도 없이?
난 도저히 이해가 안 돼
Could you talk to me for a second?
I don't understand.
왜? 사장 부인한테
나 승진시키지 말라고 했다며?
What? You asked Peterson's wife
to make sure he wouldn't promote me.
애나벨한테 자리를 주길래
그만 둬버렸어
So he gives a huge promotion
to Annabel so I quit.
이해안되는 부분
또 있어?
What don't you understand?
좋아
OK.
알았으니까
일단 집에 가서 얘기해
OK. Could we go home
and talk about this, please?
아니, 얘기하고 싶지 않아
빨리 보내!
No, we can't. Serve it up, meat.
하루 종일 여기서
게임이나 하고 있을 거야?
You're just gonna stay here
and play games all day?
아니, 아이스크림도 사먹고
No, I'm gonna get some ice cream
호수에 가서 배도 타고
내가 하고 싶은대로 할 거야
and then I'm gonna go to the lake, maybe
rent a boat, do whatever I feel like.
- 이런!
- 신난다!
- God.
- Got you.
여보
Tom.
더 험한 말 나오기전에
얼른 내 앞에서 사라져
Go home before
I say something I regret. Go home.
네 차례야
All right. You.
앞으로 1점 더 먹으면
자전거 돌려줄게
You score this next point,
you get your bike back.
무슨 생각해?
What are you thinking about?
봄 대청소를 해야겠다고
생각하고 있었어요
I was just thinking that I need
to start spring-cleaning.
- 아직 안했어?
- 아뇨, 홈통도 닦아야하고
- You haven't done that yet?
- No, and I need to clean our gutters
냉장고 밑도 닦아야하고
and beneath the refrigerator,
찬장에 그릇받침 간지도
너무 오래됐어요
and it's so long since
I replaced the shelf liners so...
결혼할 때 받은 포크 세트는
맨 마지막이지?
You'll finish off
with our wedding silver.
어떻게 알았어요?
How did you know that?
내가 신경 안 쓰는 줄
알았겠지만 그렇지 않아
All those years, you didn't think
I was paying attention. But I was.
- 왜 맨 마지막에 하는 줄 알아요?
- 아니
- Do you know why I save it for last?
- No.
퍼른 이모가 한 말이
생각나기 때문이에요
Because it makes me think
of my Aunt Fern.
우리 결혼하던 날
너무 행복하다고 했더니
On the day we got married,
I told her how happy I was.
살면서 가끔
불행하다고 느껴질 땐
She told me that even during bad times
가장 좋은 시간은
아직 오지 않았다고 생각하랬어요
to always remember
that the best was yet to come.
그래서 그걸 닦으면서
당신, 애들, 인생...
So as I polish it, I think about you
and the kids and our life.
그리고 이모 말을 생각해요
And how right she was.
- 수술을 해야 하나 봐
- 알아요
- They're gonna operate on me.
- I know.
당신한테 할 말이 있어
내가 만약...
I wanna say some stuff.
I mean, just in case...
여보, 아무 말 하지 말아요
Rex, you don't have to say anything.
내가 잘못한 거
모두 다 사과할게
I'm sorry for everything I did.
집 나갔던 일, 외도했던 일
그리고 당신한테 시켰던 일
The moving out, the infidelity,
the sex stuff.
괜찮아요
It doesn't matter.
지금부턴 다 잊고
서로 비긴 걸로 해요
From here on in,
can we just say that we're even?
- 좋아
- 고마워요
- OK.
- Thanks.
그리고 내가 장담하는데
And for the record,
당신은 수술을
잘 견뎌낼 거예요
you are gonna come through
this operation just fine.
어떻게 확신해?
How can you be so sure?
가장 좋은 시간은
아직 오지 않았으니까요
Because I told you.
The best is yet to come.
일요일에 올게
봉고 먹이 주는 거 잊지 마
Don't forget to feed Bongo.
그래, 당장가서 줘야겠다
Thanks. I'll go do that now.
차에 타, 엄마하고 잠깐
할 얘기가 있어
Go on in the car, sweetie.
I have to talk to your mum real quick.
그래서 죄고 뭐고 상관없이
전과자 배관공하고 살겠다?
So you're gonna go live in sin
with the plumber slash ex-con?
당신이 죄 얘기하니까 웃기네
바람피운 건 죄 아닌가?
It's funny you should mention sin.
Adultery still falls in that category.
난 그런 친구가 줄리 곁에
계속 있는다는 게 싫어
I don't like the idea of this guy
being around Julie 24/7.
좋은 사람이야
He's a good person.
난 아저씨 좋아요
우리한테도 잘 해줘요
Mike's cool, Dad. He cares about us
a lot and I like having him around.
그러니까 아무 말 마세요
So don't mess this up.
들었지?
You heard the girl.
그래도 배관공이야
He's still a plumber.
착하게 굴어야 돼
You be a good boy, Bongo.
안 그럼 밥 안 준다
Or you're gonna go to bed hungry.
안녕하세요
Hi, Miss Mayer.
좀 앉아주시겠어요?
Will you sit down, please?
- 물 좀 마시고 올게
- 꼼짝 말고 있어요
- I'm just gonna go get some water.
- I'd rather you didn't.
열지 말아요
Don't answer it.
안에 있는 거 알아, 수잔
I know you're in there, Susan.
다 보여
I can see you.
나하고 얘기하기 싫으면
최소한 몸이라도 숨겨
If you don't want to talk to me, fine.
At least have the courtesy to hide.
들어오지 못하게 해요
All right, but don't let her in.
이디, 정말 반갑다
Edie, what a pleasant surprise.
그래, 마이크 있어?
Right. Is Mike home?
아니, 일이 있어서 나갔어
무슨 일인데?
No. He's on a big plumbing job.
What's up?
- 들어가도 돼?
- 왜?
- Can I come in?
- Why?
글쎄 오늘 펠리시아가
폭행을 당했다지 뭐야
I'm warning all the neighbors.
Felicia Tillman was attacked.
- 그래?
- 폴 집에서
- She was?
- At the Young house.
구급차에 실려가는 걸 보니까
무서워 죽겠어
They took her away in an ambulance.
I'm freaked out.
공사장에 인부들도
다 안 보이고
My guys haven't shown up
at the job site yet.
혼자있기 무서워서 그래
여기 잠깐만 있으면 안 될까?
I'm over there all alone. Could I just
come in and hang out for a while?
뭘 어떻게 하라고?
Stick it up my... What?
안 되겠으니까 가봐
Just get the hell out of here.
진짜 싸가지 없어
God, you are such a bitch.
이유가 뭐야?
Why?
틸만 부인한테 물었더니
사실대로 얘기 해줬어요
I asked Mrs. Tillman to tell me
the truth about my father. She did.
뭐라고 했는데?
What did she say?
델피노 씨가
아빠를 죽일거래요
Mr. Delfino took my dad away
to kill him.
그래서 나도 델피노 씨를
죽일 거예요
Now I'm gonna kill Mr. Delfino.
제가 너무 외로웠던 탓에
모두 일어난 일이에요
You Honor, this whole mess
is just a result of my loneliness.
결혼생활에
문제가 많았거든요
My marriage is a bit strained.
남편이 유죄선고를
받고 나서는...
After Carlos was convicted...
아직 유죄선고는 안 내렸어요
이건 배심원 심리입니다
No one's been convicted yet, Mrs. Solis.
This is just a grand jury hearing.
아뇨, 다른 죄에 대해서
얘기하는 거예요
No, I'm talking about
his other crime.
알겠습니다
Right.
계속 하세요
Go ahead.
어쨌든 남편은
가택구금 상태인데다가
Anyways,
he was placed under house arrest
워낙 질투심이
강한 사람이다 보니까
and he being the jealous man that he is,
제가 외출할 때마다
신경을 곤두세웠어요
got a little crazy
every time I left the house.
제가 얼마나 매력적인지
잘 아니까요
He knows how men look at me and...
그거야 뭐 어쩌겠어요?
Well, I didn't exactly ease his mind.
어쨌든 제가 바람을 피운다고
믿게 만들었어요
I falsely led him to believe
I was having an affair.
남편은 항상 일이 우선이고
절 혼자두는 일이 많아서
Before Carlos'house arrest, he was
always working and he was never with me.
제가 바람을 피운다고
생각하게 만들면
I thought that maybe if he believed
I was having an affair
절 얼마나 사랑하는지
알게 될 것 같았어요
he would realize he loved me.
바보같이 들리겠지만
그게 사실이에요
I know it sounds stupid. I do. I just...
그래서 요점이 뭡니까?
Is there a point to this?
남편이 질투심에 불타서
주먹을 휘둘렀단거죠
My point is that Carlos
is an angry, jealous Neanderthal.
게이 혐오자는 아니에요
But he's not a gay-basher.
그 정도면 충분합니다
양측 앞으로 오세요
All right. I've heard enough.
Counsel, approach.
증오범죄라고 보긴
아무래도 어려울 것 같습니다
I gotta be honest.
I don't think we have a hate crime here.
미안하지만
상대를 잘못 알았을 뿐이에요
Just so you know,
you beat up the wrong guy.
1주일에 세 번씩이나
잔디를 깎는 게
Didn't you think it was strange
that you had the only lawn
이상하다고 생각해 본 적
한 번도 없어요?
that needed to be mowed
three times a week?
죽여버리겠어
You are so dead.
- 죽여버리겠어
- 조용하세요!
- You are so dead.
- Order.
안돼요!
No. Carlos.
또 저런 짓을 하다니!
He's doing it again.
누가 좀 말려요!
For God's sake, somebody stop him.
그만해요!
Stop it.
- 조용하세요!
- 죽여버리겠어!
- We will have order.
- I'll kill you.
- 내 손에 죽을 줄 알아!
- 정숙!
- I am going to kill you.
- Order.
앉아요!
모두 조용히 하세요!
Please be seated.
We will have order.
내려요
Get out.
마사 후버가 무슨 짓을 했는지
알고 이러는 겁니까?
I'm not trying to justify anything
but Martha Huber ruined lives.
우리 가족을
철저하게 파괴했어요
For fun. She destroyed my family.
- 그 여자 때문이 아니오
- 무슨 말이죠?
- This isn't about her.
- I don't understand.
걸어요
Walk.
처음에 검사했을 때
칼륨 수치가 높았던 거 알지?
Remember when we first tested you,
your potassium level was a bit high?
그래, 그래서 바나나는
먹지 말라고 했잖아
Yes. You made me stop eating bananas.
그런데 수치가 그 후에도
계속 올라갔어
But as we've continued testing,
it's kept climbing.
기능검사를 전부
다시 했는데
We've now run an entire battery of tests
신장기능은 정상이야
and your kidney function is fine.
결국은 음식물 섭취에
이상이 있었단 얘기지
It has to be something you're ingesting.
어디 봐
Let me see.
뭐가 잘못된 거 아냐?
These numbers can't be right.
식사준비는 누가 했어?
Who prepares your meals?
집사람
Bree.
두 사람 결혼생활에
문제가 있다는 거 알아
I understand you've been having
some marital problems.
- 잠깐만
- 샐러드 바 사건 기억나?
- Wait a minute.
- Was there an incident at a salad bar?
알레르기가 있다는 걸 알면서
샐러드에 양파를 넣었었지
She gave you onions
when she knew you were allergic.
그건 사고였어
That was an accident.
분명히 음식에
문제가 있었어
You're getting this potassium
from somewhere.
- 나가
- 렉스
- Get out.
- Rex.
듣기 싫어
I mean it.
나가
Get out.
그건 두고 가
Leave the chart.
읽어봐야겠어
I want to read it.
재미있게 지냈어?
So did you have a fun day?
그래, 아주 즐거웠어
As a matter of fact, I did.
이렇게 즐거운 게
얼마만인지 모르겠어
I probably had the most fun
that I have had in a long time.
난 그만두라고 한 적 없어
You know, I didn't tell you to quit.
그래
No.
하지만 앞으로 20년 동안은
꼼짝 못하게 만들었지
But you made damn sure that
I'd go nowhere for the next 20 years.
뭐라고 할 말이 없어
I don't know what to say.
이럴 땐 보통
미안하다고들 하지
I hear "Please forgive me" is popular.
그래, 미안해
정말 미안해
Yes, I am sorry. I am so, so sorry.
하지만 당신한테
상처를 주려던 건 아냐
I didn't want to hurt you.
난 우리 가족을
지키고 싶었어
But I was trying to protect our family.
당신이 승진했다면
얼굴도 보기 힘들었을 테고...
If you got a promotion, we never would
have seen you. You would have been...
됐어, 당신 말이 맞아
Lynette, you're right.
당신 말이 다 맞아
승진했으면 우린 끝장났어
You're right. You're right. That
promotion would have just killed us.
차라리 이렇게 된 게
더 잘된 건지도 몰라
So this is gonna all work out.
그건 무슨 뜻이야?
What does that mean?
일을 안하겠다는 뜻이지
It means that I can use the break.
그래, 당분간 좀 쉬는 건
나쁠 거 없어
Well, yeah. I think it would be good
for you to take some time off.
아니, 당분간이 아니라
계속 놀겠단 뜻이야
No, not some time. Full-time.
앞으론 계속
집에 있을 거야
I'm gonna be a stay-at-home dad.
안될 거 없잖아
당신이 나가서 벌어
What the heck?
You earn the living for a while.
그건 말도 안돼
Tom, that's crazy.
왜?
말 안될 거 없어
Why? Why is it crazy?
당신이 나보다 낫다는 거
우리 둘 다 아는 사실이잖아
You and I both know
that you're better at the ad game.
그리고 애들 보기 힘들다고
늘 불평하지 않았어?
And you tell me all the time
how hard it is to be a mum.
그래, 힘든 건 사실이야
하지만 난 좋아
Well, yes, it is hard.
But I love it, too.
집에 있었던 6년 내내
불평만 한 건 아니잖아
I've been doing it for six years and
I haven't complained the entire time.
그래
Fair enough.
하지만 솔직해져 봐
But be honest.
속으로는 광고판이 그립지?
Secretly, you miss the ad game,
don't you?
마감에 쫓기는 스트레스
치열한 점심시간까지 말이야
You miss the pressure
and the deadlines and the power lunches.
내 말이 틀렸어?
Or am I wrong?
평생 더러운 양말이나 빨면서
살고 싶은 건 아니잖아
Maybe you want to sort dirty socks
the rest of your life.
성급하게 결론 내리지 말고
차근차근 얘기해봐
We should talk about this seriously
before we make any rash decisions.
난 벌써 결정했어
당신이 나가서 일해
I already made the decision.
You're going back to work.
먹을 것 좀 줄까?
Can I at least
get you something to eat, Zach?
음료수요, 고마워요
Maybe a soda. Thanks.
넌 지금 실수하는 거야
I gotta say,
I think you're making a mistake.
마이크는 사람을 죽이지 못 해
Mike couldn't kill anybody.
네가 뭔가
오해하고 있는 걸 거야
I mean, this could just be
a misunderstanding.
오해 아니에요
This is not a misunderstanding.
화나있는 거 알아
I know you're upset,
하지만 이렇게 하는 걸
엄마가 좋아하실까?
but is this what you think
your mother would want you doing?
- 그렇지 않겠죠
- 맞아
- Probably not.
- Exactly.
엄마가 널
얼마나 정성껏 키우셨니?
Because she raised you right.
그 동안 엄마 일 때문에
힘들었던 것도 알고
Look, you have been through a lot.
You've lost your mum.
여동생 일 때문에
죄책감 느끼는 것도 알아
You're still carrying the guilt
of what happened to your baby sister.
- 여동생 같은 건 없었어요!
- 데이나 일 나도 다 알아
- I never had a baby sister.
- Honey, I know about Dana.
어떻게 그렇게 멍청해요?
내가 데이나예요!
How stupid are you? I'm Dana.
마약중독자가 친 엄마래요
날 훔쳐서 이름을 바꿨대요!
My mother was some junkie.
They stole me and changed my name.
지금까지 계속 날 속였어요
모두 날 속였다고요!
They have been lying to me
my entire life. Everyone lies to me.
엄마, 아빠
틸만 부인, 줄리까지요!
My mother, my father,
Mrs. Tillman, even Julie.
그게 얼마나
가슴 아픈 일인지 알아요?
Do you understand how much that hurts?
잠깐만, 재크
Look, Zach.
화난 거 알아
우리 앉아서 얘기하자
I know you're upset.
Let's just sit down and talk.
왜요?
또 무슨 거짓말을 하게요?
Why? So you can lie to me also?
아무 말도 하지 말아요
No more talking.
"여보..."
"당신을 이해해
그리고 당신을 용서하겠어"
- 여보세요?
- 브리? 리 크레이그예요
- Hello?
- Bree, it's Dr. Craig.
여기 병원이에요
나쁜 소식이 있어요
I'm at the hospital
and I'm afraid I have some bad news.
10분 전에
렉스가 떠났어요
Rex passed away ten minutes ago.
하지만 내일이 수술이잖아요
But his operation is not until tomorrow.
그때까지 버티지 못했어요
I know. He just didn't make it.
미안해요
최선을 다한 건 알아줘요
I'm so sorry.
We did everything we could.
- 브리?
- 네, 알아요
- Bree?
- Yes. Of course you did.
전화 고마워요
Thank you very much for calling.
이렇게 멀리까지 나올 필요는
없었잖아요
This is a long way to go to do what you
could have done in my back yard.
오래 걷는 건
시간낭비예요
You're kind of taking your time.
Walking a lot.
지금 뭘 하려는 건진 알아요?
사람 죽여본 적 있어요?
You sure you know what you're doing? You
ever had to kill anyone for real before?
그래요
Yeah.
하지만 걷는 게 힘들다니
여기서 합시다
But since you're so tired of walking,
let's just do this here.
마지막으로 이거 하나만
물어봅시다
I don't expect any favors from you,
obviously.
도대체 여기까지 날
끌고 온 이유가뭡니까?
But could you at least do me the
courtesy of telling me why we're here?
데어드레를 알아요?
You knew Deidre.
그래요
Yeah.
데어드레에게
무슨 짓을 했는지도 알아요
And I know what you did to her.
문제가 많은 여자였죠
She was just a sad girl
with a lot of problems.
아주 형편없고 제멋대로에
엉망이었어요
She did some terrible, crazy,
selfish stuff.
하지만 당신같은 사람손에
죽을 만큼
But you tell me what she
ever could have done to deserve death
가치 없는 여자는
아니었어요
at the hands of somebody like you.
그렇게 됐어요
It's complicated.
그럴 수밖에 없었어요
It's so complicated.
그렇게 남편은 내 비밀을
털어놓기 시작했다
And just like that,
my husband began sharing my secrets.
당근 줄까, 재커리?
You want some carrot, Zachary?
내가 목숨을 걸고
지키려고 했던 비밀을...
Secrets I had died to protect.
여기 있다
There you go.
수영장 공사 끝나기 전에
담부터 빨리 높여야겠어요
We have to get that fence up in the
back yard before the pool's finished.
- 알아
- 대답만 하지 말고요
- I know.
- I'm serious.
잘못하면
애들 다 빠지겠어요
You know kids are drawn to water.
안녕, 앤젤라
Hello, Angela.
아주 꼭꼭 숨은 덕분에
You did a good job covering your tracks.
찾는데 돈이 많이 들었어
I had to spend
a lot of money hunting you down.
어쨌든 찾았으니
축하해야겠네
Congratulations. You found us.
경찰엔 말 안 했어
You know, I never
told the police what happened.
그래요?
You didn't?
말했으면 데이나를
보호시설에 넘기거나
They would have put Dana in foster care.
아버지한테 줬을 테니까
Or worse, given him to my father.
그래서 비밀을 지킨거야
So I kept our little secret.
그건 고맙게 생각해요
Well, we appreciate that.
그리고 보면 알겠지만
약은 완전히 끊었어
Anyway, I guess you can see
I've gotten myself cleaned up.
그래, 아주 좋아보여
Yes, you look lovely.
이젠 옛날의 내가 아냐
I'm not the same person
you knew back then, Angela.
사는 곳도 제법 괜찮아
I'm in a good place now.
애를 데려갈 순 없어
You can't have him.
지금이라도 당장
경찰에 갈 수 있어
I didn't go to the police before
but I can do it now.
- 재크는 우리 아들이야!
- 그 애 이름은 데이나야
- Zach is our son.
- His name is Dana.
너 같은 중독자한테
내 아들을 줄 것 같아?
If you think I'm giving my baby
to some junkie, you're crazy.
- 그 앤 내 아들이야
- 진정해요
- He's not your baby.
- Just calm down.
항상 고고하고
품위 있는 시선으로
You were always so high and mighty,
우리를 깔보듯이
내려다 본 거 알아
looking down on us poor degenerates,
도움을 주는 척 했지만 실은
우월감을 느끼고 싶었던 거지
pretending you wanted to help when all
you really wanted was to feel superior.
- 이기적인 인간!
- 약 끊지 않았어
- You self-righteous bitch.
- You're still using.
지옥에나 떨어져!
뭐 하는거야!
Go to hell. What are you doing?
- 팔을 봐야겠어
- 깨끗하다고 했잖아
- Let me see your arm.
- I said I'm clean.
- 좀 진정해
- 어디 가는거야?
- Just take it easy.
- Where do you think you're going?
내 아들을 데리고
집으로 갈거야
I'm getting my son and taking him home.
- 얼른 잡아요!
- 이리와요
- Paul, stop her.
- Please. Come on.
- 앉아요!
- 이거 놔!
- Sit down.
- Get your hands off me.
지금껏 우리가 키웠어
우리가 그 애 부모야
We raised him. We're his parents.
이러지 말아요
Come on.
여보!
Paul.
걱정마
좋은 환경에서 키울거야
Don't worry. I'll give him a good home.
안돼!
No.
여보...
무슨 짓을 한거야?
Mary Alice. What did you do?
엄마?
Mummy?
괜찮아, 재크
It's OK, Zach.
네 장난감 상자 좀
빌려야겠어
Mummy needs to borrow your toy chest.
얼른 다시 자
You go back to sleep, OK?
어떻게 할 거야?
What are we gonna do?
내일 수영장에
시멘트를 붓는다고 했죠?
You said they were pouring the concrete
for the pool tomorrow?
- 진심이야?
- 절대 못 찾을 거예요
- You can't be serious.
- They'll never find her.
- 이 상자 안에 넣어야겠어요
- 크기가 안맞아
- We can put her in this.
- She won't fit.
그럼 맞게 만들어야죠
Then we'll have to make her fit.
- 뭐 하는 거야?
- 주사자국 찾아요
- What are you doing?
- Checking for track marks.
아기가 있었어요?
Deidre had a baby?
얼른 끝냅시다
Let's get this over with.
내가 두고 온 세상을
되돌아 볼 때마다
It's an odd thing
to look back on the world,
난 이상한 생각을
떨쳐 버릴 수가 없다
to watch those I left behind,
친구들은 저마다
용감하고 과감하지만
each, in her own way,
so brave, so determined,
저마다 절망을 안고 있다
and so very desperate.
새로운 도전을
시작하려 하지만
Desperate to venture out,
잃게 될 것들에 대한
두려움을 떨치지 못한다
but afraid of what she'll miss
when she goes.
원하는 모든 것을
갖고자 하지만
Desperate to get everything she wants,
자신이 원하는 것이
무엇인지도 알지 못한다
even when she's not exactly sure
of what that is.
완벽한 예전 생활로
돌아가고 싶어하지만
Desperate for life to be perfect again,
실은 한 번도 완벽한 적이
없었다는 것을 잘 안다
although she realizes
it never really was.
더 나은 미래를 꿈꾸지만
Desperate for a better future,
아직 과거에서 조차
빠져 나오지 못 하고 있다
if she can find a way
to escape her past.
하지만 난 이 멋진 친구들을
지켜보면서 응원을 보낸다
I not only watch, I cheer them on,
these amazing women.
그들이 찾는 것을
모두 찾게 되기를 바라며...
I hope so much
they'll find what they're looking for.
하지만 아무도
그러지 못 할 것을 잘 알고 있다
But I know not all of them will.
슬프지만
Sadly...
그게 바로
인생의 법칙이기 때문이다
that's just not the way life works.
모두가 해피엔딩을
장식할 순 없다는 것
Not everyone gets a happy ending.